Guide to the Carl Gustav Hempel Papers, 1903-1997 ASP.1999.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Correspondence, 1924-1997; II.
  - General Correspondence, 1930-1996; 1.
    - Dennett Philosophical Lexicon—Desjardins, Paul, 1967-1978 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Deutscher Taschenbuch-Verlag,; see also CH 23-04 "Lenzen, Wolfgang", 1974-1975 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Devenish, Philip, E.—Dickinson Publishing, 1962-1980 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Diemer, Alvin & Zeitschrift für Allgemeine Wissenschaftstheorie, 1965-1974 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Dietl, Paul—Duda, William, 1944-1990 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Dudzus, Renate—Duke University Press, 1976-1988 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Earman, John, 1967-1992 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Eberlein, Gerald and Hans-Joachim von Kondratowitz, 1971-1974 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Economos, Judith, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Eckstein, Harry: see folder CH 34-12 "Small, Michael" (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Edel, Abe (Abraham) (CCNY), 1962-1971 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Edwards, Paul, 1956-1972 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Ehrlich, Philip—Embree, Lester re. Felix Kaufmann, 1950-1993 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Encyclopedia Americana "Meaning"—Erlichster, Joe, 1951-1983 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Essler, Wilhelm and Journal Erkenntnis, 1983-1991 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Essler, Wilhelm and Journal Erkenntnis, 1980-1982 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Essler, Wilhelm and Journal Erkenntnis, 1977-1979 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Essler, Wilhelm and Journal Erkenntnis, 1975-1976 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Essler, Wilhelm (Wolfgang Stegmüller) re. Revival of Journal Erkenntnis, 1972-1974 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Fabian, Dorothy—Feferman, Solomon, 1956-1990 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Feigl, Herbert, 1959-1988 (Box 16, Folder 01-03)
    - Fermat, Pierre de and Andrew J. Wiles—Festschrift Hempel, 1985 and 1993 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Fetzer, Jim, 1972-1992 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Feuer, Lewis S.—Foster, Lawrence, 1951-1977 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Fraenkel, Abraham H.—Frankel, Charles, 1949-1979 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Frankfurt: Ad Provisio Lecture & Honorary Doctorate, 1979, 1986-1987 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Franks, Abbie, 1952 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Free Press I: Correspondence re. Aspects of Scientific Explanation, 1959-1973 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Free Press II: Annual Statements, Reviews, Permissions File for Aspects of Scientific Explanation, 1956-1977 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Freeman, Eugene, 1972-1976 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Freie Universität Berlin, Honorary Degree, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - French Line—Friedrich, Carl J., 1958-1991 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Fried, Michael, (Letter), 1996 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Friedman, Michael, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Fulbright, 1958-1960 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - G., O. (Berlin)—Gay, Peter, 1933-1991 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Georgetown University, 1977-1983 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Georgia Tech, Fall 1967, 1967-1975 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Geraets, Theodore—Ginsburg, Jerry, 1963-1987 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Gladstone, Arthur—Glymour, Bruce D., 1953-1992 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Glymour, Clark, 1972-1977 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Gödel, Kurt, 1930-1931 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Goe, George, 1969-1974 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Goheen, John D., 1949-1972 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Goldstein, Leon J., 1962-1984 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Goode, Terry, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Goodman, Nelson (Philos. 531 '70), 1949-1992 (Box 18, Folder 06-07)
    - Goodman Symposium—APA, Dec. 1979, 1979-1980 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Gorowitz, Samuel—Gould, Anne, 1967-1979 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Grandy, Richard, 1971-1978 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Granger, Gilles—Greene, Theodore M., 1953-1973 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Gregg, John R., 1951-1967 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Grelling, Kurt, Material regarding Kurt Grelling, 1974-1987 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Grice, Paul and Kathleen, 1962-1967 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Grünbaum, Adolf, 1960-1993 (Box 19, Folder 06-08)
    - Gulbenkian Foundation—Gustavus Adolphus College, 1964-1981 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Hackett, William H.Y. and Frances, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Hacking, Ian, 1961-1974 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Haggerson, Nelson L.—Hamline University, 1952-1986 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Hampshire, Stuart—Hartshorne, Charles, 1958-1987 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Harvard University (incl. correspondence with Quine), 1953-1975 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Harvard University Press, 1950-1979 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Harvard Reading Courses (Bromberger, Quimby, Shapere), 1954 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Harvard: Visiting Committee, 1970-1973 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Hattiangadi, Jagdish—Haynes, Michael, 1952-1987 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Hebrew University, 1972-1975 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Hegenberg, Leonidas—Hellman, Geoffrey, 1975, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Helmer, Olaf, 1950-1992 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Hempel: Festschrift, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Hempel: Festschrift, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 11B)
    - Hempel Honorary Degree: University of Pittsburgh, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Hempel Interview for Mishkenot Sha'ananim by Edna Ullman-Margalit, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Hempel's Raven Paradox, 1984-1988 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Hendel, Charles—Henry, Barklie McKee (Buz), 1959-1969 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Henson, Richard, 1956-1967 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Hentschel, Klaus—Hilpinen, Risto, 1962-1991 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Hintikka, Jaakko, 1952-1975 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Hirshberg, W.L. (Philosophy of Science Assoc.)—Hofstadter, Albert, 1950-1992 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Holmes, Roger, 1957-1972 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Holsen, Rebecca, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Holton, Gerald, 1968-1983 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Hook, Sidney, 1949-1968 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Hooker, C.A.—Hoy, David and Joyce, 1955-1991 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Hosiasson (Lindenbaum), Janina, 1938-1939 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Hrushovski, Benjamin, 1984-1986 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Hübner, Kurt, 1971-1975 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Hull, David—Hung, Tscha, 1974-1996 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Hunter, Geoffrey—Imhof, Florian von, 1954-1980 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Institute for Advanced Study, Princeton, 1970-1973 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Institute for the Future, 1967-1969 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Institute for International Education, 1961-1965 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Institute for the Unity of Science, 1971-1976 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Institute Vienna Circle, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - International Conference on the Unity of the Sciences, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - International Congress for Logic, Methodology and Philosophy of Science, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - International Cultural Foundation (Rev. Moon)—Intisar-Ul-Haque, Dr., 1964-1983 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Invitations: Lectures, etc., (Part of Correspondence Discarded), 1956-1977 (Box 22, Folder 06-07)
    - Invitations; Writing, 1967-1977 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - IPN Institute, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Isenberg, Arnold, 1951-1971 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Israel Academy of Sciences and Humanities—Jammer, Max, 1969-1979 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Janich, Peter, 1974-1975 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Jenkins, Iredell—Jones, George Jr., 1950-1979 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Jeffrey, Richard, 1962-1964 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Journal of Symbolic Logic, 1936-1965 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Journal of Philosophy, 1973-1990 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Kahane, Howard, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Kaila, Eino: Symposium Eino Kaila and Logical Empiricism, Helsinki, Oct. 4, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Kalke, William—Kaplan, Abraham, 1952-1993 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Kaplan, David, 1962-1972 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Kasher, ASA: See PHILOSOPHIA (TEL-AVIV) (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Katz, Jerrold—Kaufmann, Felix, 1949-1979 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Kaufmann, Walter, 1957-1980 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Kauppi, Raili—Kelley, Stan, 1985-1991 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Kemeny, John, 1954-1977 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Kempski, Jürgen von—Ketonen, Oiva, 1948-1978 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Kim, Jaegwon, 1962-1987 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - King-Farlow, John—Kitagawa, Hidenori, 1966-1979 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Kitcher, Philip, 1972-1990 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Kitts, David B., 1961-1976 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Kleene, S.C.—Knowles, Clayton (NY Times), 1951-1992 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Kluwer Academic Publisher, Financial Material, 1995 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Köhl, Harald—Koopmans, Tjalling C., 1955-1992 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Kopfermann, Hans, 1948-1973 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Kordig, Carl R.—Krízek, Richard, 1971-1991 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Koutouzos, Eurysthenes, 1984-1985 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Krüger, Lorenz, 1968-1986 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Kruskal, William, 1966 and 1973 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Kuhn, Thomas, 1967-1991 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Kuipers, Theo A.F.—Kurosaki, Hiroshi, 1971 and 1992 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Kutschera, Franz von, 1971-1972 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Kyburg, Henry E., 1964-1983 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Lachmann, Irena and Feliks, 1980-1981 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Lakatos, Imre, 1964-1974 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Lambert, Karel - Lamont, 1955-1972 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Laudan, Larry, 1971-1991 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Laue, Tim, 1981-1992 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Lange, John F. - Lange, Marc, 1971 and 1992 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Latsis, Spiro (see also: LSE), 1972-1977 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Lawson, Warren, 1967-1968 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Lazarowitz, Alice, 1952-1974 (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - Lazarsfeld, Paul F., 1950-1961 (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - Leach, James J. - Ledermann, Walter, 1963-1986 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Lehman, Hugh - Lehrer, Keith, 1963-1970 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Leibowitz, Yeshayahu - Lenk, Hans, 1972-1983 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Lenz, John W. - Leonard, Henry S., 1956-1976 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Leplin, (Jarret?) - Levey, Irving M., 1969-1979 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Levi, Isaac, 1960-1981 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Levin, Michael E. – Libby, Tony and Marion, 1959-1976 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Lin, Chao-tien – Lipkin, Robert, 1972-1991 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Liu, Shih Chao – London School of Economics, 1957-1976 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - London, University of—Lowe, Adolph, 1965-1986 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Lvey, Michael L.—Lynton, Ernest, 1948-1981 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Mackie, J. L. (John Leslie): see folder CH 32-11 "Salmon, Wesley"
    - Machlup, Fritz—Madden, Edward, 1951-1993 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Mainzer—Magdalen College School, 1962-1981 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Mandelbaum, Maurice, 1955-1981 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Maher, Patrick L.—Mandler, George, 1954-1986 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Manhattanville College—Marantz, Frederick, 1964 –1972 (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Marcus, Ruth Barcan—Margelit, Edna, 1962–1984 (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Margenau, Henry—Martin, John F., 1953-1972 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Martin, Michael—Martin, Richard M., 1950-1992 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Mason, Perry C.—Mason, Robert G., 1963-1977 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Massey, Barbara, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Massey, Gerald J. (Jerry), 1963-1991 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Matheson, Gordon, 1961-1978 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Maxwell, Grover—Mayr, Ernst, 1975-1983 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Mayer, Ruth L. MD—McKeon, Richard, 1954-1991 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - McMullin, Ernan, 1971-1992 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - McMurrin, Sterling—Meggle, Georg, 1953-1977 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Mehlberg, Henry, 1954-1976 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Mehrtens, Herbert—Mellor, D.H., 1971-1984 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Mendel, Arthur, (Esp. on Fallout Shelters), 1961-1963 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Meng, John J., 1955-1969 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Menger, Karl, 1955-1956 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Merton, Robert K.,—Mink, Louis, 1952-1976 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous, 1962-1973 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - MIT (Massachusetts Institute of Technology), 1963-1982 (Box 27, Folder 01-02)
    - Mitroff, Ian I., 1973 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Mittelstrass, Jürgen, 1974-1984 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Mochimaru, Etsuro—The Monist, 1971-1975 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Moore, G.E., 1941 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Morgenbesser, Sidney, 1959 – 1988 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Morgenstern, Oskar, 1966-1977 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Morris, Charles W., 1942 – 1988 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Morrison, Donald—Mundy, Brent H., 1972-1989 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Munevar, Gonzalo—Myhill, John, 1951-1984 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Nagasaka, Francis G., 1968-1974 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Nagel, Ernest: 1) Memorial Service, Columbia University, 2) Memoir, A.P.S. Yearbook, 1985-1990 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Nagel, Ernest, 1950-1962 (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - Letter from Hempel to Ernest Nagel, January 9, 1962; 1.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, May 14, 1962; 2.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, January 6, 1961; 3.
      - Letter from Hempel to Ernest Nagel, November 17, 1961; 4.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, December 30, 1960; 5.
      - Letter from Hempel to Ernest Nagel, January 3, 1961; 6.
      - Letter from Hempel to Ernest Nagel, December 2, 1960; 7.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, October 12, 1960; 8.
      - Charles Scribner's Sons Announcement of Ernest Nagel as Advisory Editor in Philosophy, 9.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, April 8, 1959; 10.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, May 14, 1959; 11.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, January 27, 1959; 12.
      - Letter from Hempel to Ernest Nagel, January 24, 1959; 13.
      - Letter from Hempel to Ernest Nagel, December 6, 1958; 14.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, December 1, 1958; 15.
      - Letter from Hempel to Ernest Nagel, November 23, 1958; 16.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, November 16, 1958; 17.
      - Letter from Hempel to Ernest Nagel, November 8, 1958; 18.
      - Postcard from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, September 23, 1958; 19.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, July 30, 1958; 20.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, July 11, 1958; 21.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, April 14, 1958; 22.
      - Letter from Hempel to Ernest Nagel, April 12, 1958; 23.
      - Letter from Hempel to "John", April 12, 1958; 24.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, April 3, 1958; 25.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, January 21, 1958; 26.
      - Letter from Hempel to Ernest Nagel, January 13, 1958; 27.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, December 28, 1957; 28.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, November 29, 1957; 29.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, November 15, 1957; 30.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, October 28, 1957; 31.
      - Letter from Hempel to Ernest Nagel, November 1, 1957; 32.
      - Letter from Hempel to Ernest Nagel, January 31, 1957; 33.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, January 21, 1957; 34.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, October 24, 1956; 35.
      - Letter from Hempel to Ernest Nagel, April 25, 1956; 36.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, April 22, 1956; 37.
      - Letter from Hempel to Ernest Nagel, January 31, 1956; 38.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, January 28, 1956; 39.
      - Letter from Hempel to Ernest Nagel, January 27, 1956; 40.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, January 7, 1956; 41.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, December 19, 1955; 42.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, April 3, 1955; 43.
      - Letter from Hempel to Ernest Nagel, January 27, 1955; 44.
      - Letter from Hempel to Ernest Nagel, January 13, 1955; 45.
      - Postcard from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, May 16, 1955; 46.
      - Postcard from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, December 3, 1955; 47.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, undated; 48.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, December 18, 1954; 49.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, October 11, 1954; 50.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, December 6, 1954; 51.
      - Letter from Hempel to Ernest Nagel, October 9, 1954; 52.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, September 30, 1954; 53.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, August 30, 1954; 54.
      - Letter from Hempel to Ernest Nagel, May 31, 1954; 55.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, May 27, 1954; 56.
      - Letter from Hempel to Ernest Nagel, May 24, 1954; 57.
      - Letter from Hempel to Ernest Nagel, February 26, 1954; 58.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, January 3, 1954; 59.
      - Letter from Hempel to Ernest Nagel, November 7, 1953; 60.
        Access Restrictions
        Discussion of recommendations of position at John Hopkins University.
      - Postcard from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, October 11, 1953; 61.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, October 8, 1953; 62.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, February 28, 1952; 63.
      - Letter from Hempel to Ernest Nagel, November 23, 1951; 64.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, September 1, 1951; 65.
      - Letter from Hempel to Ernest Nagel, September 15, 1950; 66.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, September 7, 1950; 67.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, July 3, 1950; 68.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, May 17, 1950; 69.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, March 7, 1950; 70.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, April 20, 1950; 71.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, April 8, 1950; 72.
      - Letter from Hempel to Ernest Nagel, April 6, 1950; 73.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, March 27, 1950; 74.
      - Letter from Hempel to Ernest Nagel, March 26, 1950; 75.
      - Letter from Hempel to Ernest Nagel, March 10, 1950; 76.
      - Letter from Ernest Nagel to Hempel, February 6, 1950; 77.
      - Letter from Hempel to Ernest Nagel, February 5, 1950; 78.
    - Nagel, Ernest, 1963-1979 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Nagel, Thomas—Nash, Leonard K., 1951-1978 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1971-1981 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - National Science Foundation: Records Referring to Hempel's Membership on Pannel, 1961-1973 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - National Science Foundation: Reviews of Proposals, 1979-1986 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - National Science Foundation: Grants to Hempel, 1967–1983 (Box 28, Folder 07-09)
    - Nehamas, Alexander—Ness, Arne, 1964 –1991 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Neurath—Hempel Correspondence 1934-1935: Copies from the Neurath Archive Amsterdam, 1934-1982 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Neurath—Hempel Correspondence: Copies from the Archives of Scientific Philosophy, 1934-1935 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Neurath, Otto and Marie, 1939-1973 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Neurath, Paul and Marie and Related Correspondence, 1947-1964 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - New Jersey Division of Moter Vehicles—NIAS (Netherlands Institute for Advanced Study in the Humanities and Social Sciences), 1963-1979 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Nickles, Tom, 1968-1984 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Nieli, Russ – Nolen (1974 Tenants), 1974-1991 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Nollan Interview of C.G. Hempel, March 1982, 1982-1983 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Nollan, Richard, 1982-1987 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Nominazione (Journal) —Northwestern University (incl. Photos), 1940-1982 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Notre Dame, University of, 1971-1975 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Novakavic, Stanisa—Open University Library, 1963-1993 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Oppenheim, Paul and Gabrielle, 1966-1970 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Österreichischer Rundfunk (ORF), 1972-1983 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Owen, David—Oxford University Press, 1954-1979 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Palombi, Ernesto—Patmos Verlag, 1952-1991 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Patton, Thomas E., 1963-1969 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Patzig, Günther, 1974-1976 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Pearce, David—Pennsylvania Academy of Science, 1977-1990 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Pera, Marcello, 1980-1992 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Permission to Reprint Publications of C. G. Hempel, 1951-1985 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Perry, Ralph Barton—Philosophical Research Center, Athens, 1955-1981 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Philosophy Delegation to the People's Republic of China (William L. McBride), 1996 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Philosophy of Science Association and Journal, 1959-1984 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Photographs at Various Occasions, 1978-1985 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Pirone, Florindo—Pop, Ileana, 1964-1991 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Popper, Karl, 1939-1985 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Population Control—Posner, Roland, 1972-1991 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Positions Offered, Invitations, 1961-1973 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Post, John F.—Prawitz, Dag, 1956-1973 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Posy, Carl, 1979-1981 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Prentice-Hall, 1959-1983 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Prentice-Hall: Philosophy of Natural Science Adoption by Universities 1966-1976 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Prentice-Hall Royalty Statements, 1966-1990 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Price, H. H., 1959 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Princeton University re. Honorary Degree, 1979 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Princeton University: Departmental Letters, Grad. Student Reports, Hempel's Publications, 1970-1995 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Princeton: Correspondence re. Offers by Harvard and Rockefeller Universities, 1967-1973 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Princeton University: Personal Documents, 1952-1977 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Princeton University Press, 1968-1970 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Prometheus Books—Pusey, Nathan M., 1963-1991 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Putnam, Hillary, 1954-1985 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Putnam, Erna, 1962 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Pyke, Steve: Philosophers Exhibition, 1991 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Quade, Anne, 1983 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Queens College, 1940-1978 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Quine, Douglas Boynton, 1972-1979 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Quine, Willard van Orman, 1950-1992 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Quinn, Philip L., 1969-1980 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Rad, M. (Tehran)—Radner, Michael, 1969-1975 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Railton, Peter, 1976-1990 (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - RAND Corp. 1946-1967 (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Rand, Rose, 1945-1963 (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Rapp, Fritz—Ratner, Sidney, 1965-1977 (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - Realgynasium Pankow 1984-1986 (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - Rebhun, L & M., 1969-1976 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Reichenbach Rememberance Reunion April 2, 1991 (Hilary Putnam) (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Reichenbach-Hempel Corresp. (from Pitt Archives) + Corresp. With Mia Reichenbach, Dec. 15, 1929-Dec. 21, 1951 1968-1970 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Reichenbach-Zilsel Corresp. (From the A.S.P.), 1925-1991 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Reichenbach, Hans Jr., and Mia, 1952-1985 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Reidel, 1971-1988 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Reisch, George A.—Resnick, Michael, 1952-1991 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Rescher, Nicholas, 1949-1991 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Response Program, 1963 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Revue Internationale De Philosophie (Lameere), 1949-1978 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Rigamonti, Gianni—Roberts, W.H., 1964-1990 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1950-1971 (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Rockefeller Institute, 1964-1968 (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Rockport (Maps), 1942-1957 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Roebuck, Joseph—Rorty, Amelia and Richard, 1955-1990 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Rosenberg, Jerry—Routley, Richard, 1951-1986 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Rudner, Richard, 1958-1978 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Rudner Memorial: Correspondence and Rudner Paper:, 1979-1981 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Ruimschotel, Richard—(Re.) Russel, Bertrand, 1940-1984 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Russell Sage Foundation, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Rutgers University, 1983 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Ruytinx, Jacques—Saint-Sernin, Bertraud, 1937-1977 (Box 34, Folder 9)